PIXAR IN A BOX 艾墨镇 aimozhen.com/pixarinabox
盒子中的皮克斯 艾墨镇 aimozhen.com/pixarinabox
- What's the difference between motion and life?
机械和生命有什么区别？
What's the difference between this mechanical smile
这个机械式的微笑和这个友好的微笑 之间有什么区别？
It's a little harder to find,
这有点难以回答
but there's just something
它与生命体的运动方式有关
And we work incredibly hard to capture
在皮克斯 我们为表现角色运动付出了
with our characters here at Pixar
令人难以置信的努力
and that something start
而这
with a stage we call rigging.
都是从一个称之为绑定的阶段开始的
Hi, I'm Brian Green,
大家好 我是 Brian Green
a Rigging Technical Director here at Pixar.
皮克斯的绑定技术总监
Rigging is a process of adding controls
绑定是一个
to a digital model
向数字模型添加控制的流程
to allow animators to move it around and act.
以便让动画师能够四处移动它们并进行表演
When you look at the way a living being moves,
当你观察一个生命体运动方式的时候
every motion they make causes a reaction
可以发现它们每次运动都引起
in every other part of their body.
身体其他部位的反应
For instance, when I smile,
比如当我微笑的时候
it's not just my lips have moved,
不只是我的嘴唇移动了
my cheeks bulge,
我的脸颊也鼓起来
the skin around my eyes crinkle.
我的眼睛也皱起来
My chin stretches out to accommodate the emotion.
我的下巴伸出以便适应我的情绪
We call this defamation and displacement.
我们把这称之为形变和位移
Arrlalalala.
Arrlalalala
In rigging, we have a toolbox
绑定的时候 我们有一个工具箱
of hundreds of different deformers
包含了上百个不同变形器
and we can attach to
我们可以把它连接到
the surface mesh of our characters.
角色的表面网格模型上
All of them represent mathematical formulas
它们代表的是一些数学公式
that define a relationship between the many points
这些公式描述了
that are affected by the motion.
那些被运动影响的点之间的关系
For instance, I can start rigging Sully's mouth
比如我可以给苏利文的嘴巴做绑定
by adding a simple deformer called a rotate.
通过添加一个名为“旋转”的简单的变形器
The underlying math here is trigonometry.
潜藏在里边的数学是三角函数
I'm going to add another tool called a repulsor.
我们再添加一个“排斥”工具
This basically puffs things in and out.
它基本上用于进进出出地充气
Add this to the cheeks,
把它添加到脸颊处
and link them.
关联它们
And then when we move his jaw,
当我们移动他的下巴时
his cheeks bulges.
他的脸颊就会鼓起来
That's better,
这样好多了
but it's still just the beginning.
但这依然只是开始
Sully's face alone uses over 500 deformers
苏利文的脸本身用了超过500个控制器
and that's just his face.
而这仅仅只是他的脸部
We can take a similar approach to
我们也可以采用类似的方法
rigging the characters' bodies too.
来绑定角色的身体
Adding deformers that define a relationship
添加一些变形器
between the knees and the calf,
用于描述膝关节和小腿
the tail and the rump,
臀部和尾巴
or this tentacle and that tentacle.
或者这个触手和那个触手 之间的关系
After we got the physiology right,
在生理学上已经确定没问题后
we need to remember that these characters
我们需要意识到
are film actors.
这些角色是电影演员
So the kind of motion that they may need to make
所以他们所呈现的运动特征
might be a little more extreme than a regular monster.
可能会比一般的怪物更加极致一点
So we push it a little,
让我们更进一步
gives them extra life
赋予他们特别的生命
so they can be extra exciting on the screen. aimozhen.com/pixarinabox
让他们在银幕上显得格外激动人心 aimozhen.com/pixarinabox